The healthiest diet is
one that maximizes
the intake of
foods-as-grown—
whole, plant-based foods—
and minimizes the
intake of processed
and animal-
based foods.
In the first half of my
book, How Not to Die,
I cover the “why” of
eating healthfully,
exploring the role diet may
play in the prevention,
treatment, and sometimes
even reversal
of the fifteen leading
causes of death
in the United States.
In the second half,
I dive into the “how”
of eating healthfully,
which includes my
Daily Dozen checklist.
The Daily Dozen
was developed
based upon the best available
balance of evidence.
Rather than being a meal
plan or diet in itself,
it’s really just a
checklist to inspire you
to include some of the
healthiest of healthy foods
into your daily routine.
It may appear to
be a lot of boxes,
but it’s easy to check
off a bunch at a time.
For example, my
“groatnola” recipe,
which you can find
on the NutritionFacts.org
recipe page,
nails whole grains, berries,
and nuts & seeds,
in one shot.
The checklist can help
you think about
how you can improve
the nutrient density
of your meals and it can
also help you design
a more balanced meal.
Note, the Daily Dozen is
just meant to serve
as an aspirational
minimum.
Feel free to add
even more
Green Light foods
throughout your day.
We created the Daily
Dozen Challenge
to help more people
discover how to include
some of the best foods
into their daily life.
Pick a day to eat
the Daily Dozen,
and document it
on social media.
Share your challenge
experience
with friends and family
to help inspire more people
to include some of
the healthiest whole,
plant foods into
your meals.
Use the hashtag
#DailyDozenChallenge
on all your posts to
help build a community
of people taking
the challenge
and inspire even
more people to join.
Together, we can help
encourage more people
to adopt healthier habits.